# **GEORGIOS IS. DETORAKIS, PH.D.**

Almost six years of experience in industrial applications of machine and deep learning, time series analysis, natural language processing, and image processing. Eleven years of research experience in scientific laboratories of various disciplines such as computational neuroscience, machine learning, neuromorphic computing, control theory, and robotics. Strong abilities in combining and bridging different fields such as machine learning, neuroscience, computer science, and mathematics. Strong skills in machine and deep learning, dynamical systems, signal processing, mathematical modeling, and neuromorphic computing. Long experience in programming ( $\sim 27$  years) in system and scripting languages.



#### CONTACT

gdetor@protonmail.com

+1 (949) 2410844

@gdetor

in Georgios Is. Detorakis

0000-0001-5891-1702

Publications list

#### **SKILLS**

French

Science Neuroscience Machine and Deep Learning Neuromorphic Computing Signal Processing
Dynamical Systems
Programming Python C C++ Rust Shell Script Matlab/Octave LaTeX
Software & Tools
Machine Learning (e.g., Pytorch, Keras, Sklearn)
NLP (e.g., Hugging Face, spaCy) Visualisation
(e.g., Gnuplot, Paraview, Graphviz) <b>Data handling/analysis</b> (e.g., Pandas)
Numerical Libraries (e.g., FEniCS, LAPACK/BLAS)
HPC Libraries (e.g., MPI, OpenMP, CUDA) Neural Simulators
(e.g., Neuron, Brian) Linux
Languages Greek English
LIIBIIJII

### **WORK HISTORY**

# 11/2020 - Now

Independent Contractor, Irvine, CA, USA

Machine Learning Engineer

Developing and deploying machine/deep learning algorithms for time series forecasting and analysis for financial data | NLP for economic news | Deep learning for object detection, tracking & image processing | Developing controllers for TEC based on RL

**11/2020** 

adNomus Inc., San Jose, CA, USA

**Data Science Architect** 

Developed NLP algorithms for recommendation systems | Algorithms for time series (behavioral data) forecasting

**1** 02/2016 - 07/2019

**Q** University of California, Irvine, CA, USA

Postdoc Researcher

Developed algorithms for stochastic deep neural networks | Developed a neuromorphic framework, NSAT, and its simulator | Integrated neuromorphic sensors (DVS camera) with neuromorphic algorithms

**12/2013 - 12/2015** 

**♀** CentraleSupelec, Gif-sur-Yvette, France

Postdoc Researcher

Developed mathematical models for closed-loop control systems with applications for Parkinson's disease | Developed algorithms for spike-sorting and online electrophysiological recordings

#### **EDUCATION**

**10/2010 - 10/2013** 

Ph.D. in Computer Science

• University of Lorraine, Nancy (France)

Cortical plasticity, dynamic neural fields and self-organization

**1** 01/2007 - 04/2009

**♀** University of Crete, Heraklion (Greece)

M.Sc. in Brain & Mind Sciences

**1** 09/2002 - 09/2006

University of Crete, Heraklion (Greece)

B.Sc. in Applied Mathematics

Mathematical methods and software development track

#### 

GAIM

A C++ library for Genetic Algorithms and Island Models

NSA<sup>-</sup>

A C/Python simulator for the Neural and Synaptic Array Transceiver (NSAT) neuromorphic framework

NSATcarl

A C++ interface of CARLsim for the NSAT neuromorphic framework

SPySort

A Python package for spike sorting

#### SELECTED TALKS

- ★ Biologically plausible contrastive divergence: Towards an abstract complementary learning system, Hughes Research Laboratory (HRL), Malibu CA (USA), 2017
- Neural Fields 101, CentraleSupélec, Gif-sur-Yvette (France), 2015
- ★ The perception of touch: A computational approach, Aix Marseille University, Marseille (France), 2014

## **SELECTED PUBLICATIONS**

**	S. Dutta, <b>G. De</b>	g machine with stochastic synapse allows brain-like learning and inference torakis, A. Khanna, B. Grisafe, E. Neftci, and S. Datta  Nature Communications 13, 2571	
Randomized Self-Organizing Map  N.P. Rougier and G. Is. Detorakis			
₩	2021	Meural Computation, 33(8)	
	-	is of a neural field self-organizing map A. Chaillet, and N.P. Rougier	
₩	2020	■ The Journal of Mathematical Neuroscience, 10 (20)	
GAIM: A C++ library for Genetic Algorithms and Island Models  G. Detorakis, and A. Burton			
		■ The Journal of Open Source Software, 4(44), 1839	
Inherent Weight Normalization in Stochastic Neural Networks  ** G. Detorakis, S. Dutta, A. Khanna, B. Grisafe, S. Datta, and E. Neftci			
		NeurIPS (NIPS) Conference, Vancouver (Canada)	
Contrastive Hebbian Learning with Random Feedback Weights			
		T. Bartley, E. Neftci  ■ Neural Networks, 114	
	G. Detorakis, S	aptic Array Transceiver: A Brain-Inspired Computing Framework for Embedded Learning 5. Sheik, C. Augustine, S. Paul, B.U. Pedroni, N. Dutt, J. Krichmar, G. Cauwenberghs, E. Neftci Frontiers in Neuroscience (Neuromorphic section) 12	
	Event-Driven Random Back-Propagation: Enabling Neuromorphic Deep Learning Machines  L. Neftci, S. Paul, C. Augustine, <b>G. Detorakis</b>		
₩	2017	Frontiers in Neuroscience 11, 2017	
Incremental stability of spatiotemporal delayed dynamics and application to neural fields  G. Detorakis and A. Chaillet			
		Control and Decision Conference, Melbourne (Australia), 2017	
	Event-Driven Random Backpropagation: Enabling Neuromorphic Deep Learning Machines  L. Neftci, C. Augustine, S. Paul, G. Detorakis		
		■ IEEE ISCAS, Baltimore (MD, USA)	
Closed-loop stimulation of a delayed neural fields model of parkinsonian STN-GPe network: a theoretical and computational study			
<u></u>	G. Is. Detoraki	s, A. Chaillet, S. Palfi, and S. Senova	
₩	2015	Frontiers in Neuroscience, 9:237	
Structure of Receptive Fields in a Computational Model of Area 3b of Primary Sensory Cortex  G. Is. Detorakis and N.P. Rougier			
₩	2014	Frontiers in Computational Neuroscience, 8(76)	
A Neural Field Model of the Somatosensory Cortex: Formation, Maintenance and Reorganization of Ordered Topographic Maps  G. Is. Detorakis and N.P. Rougier			
₩	2012	<b>■</b> PLoS ONE 7(7): e40257	
Sel	lf-Organizing	Dynamic Neural Fields	
N.P. Rougier and G. Is. Detorakis			
₩	2011	Advances in Cognitive Neurodynamics III, Hokaido (Japan)	